<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing with Python and R</title>
      <link>/blog/practicing-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/practicing-python/</guid>
      <description>Using both R and Python at the same time can be something really fun. To show you, I’m gonna run the reticulate library to allow these different languages to communicate. Starting with R, I’m gonna assign this string of characters to “TheHonest”.
library(reticulate) TheHonest &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;Kate Bush&amp;#39;s 1982 record The Dreaming&amp;quot; Next, switching to python, I’m going to save this string of characters to “Truth”. Finally, I’m going to print out the result of both of these strings in this python code chunk using the print function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anorexia Nervosa and Genetics</title>
      <link>/anorexia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/anorexia/</guid>
      <description>The Effects of Genetically Modified Ghrelin Receptor Protein and Ghrelin O-Acyltransferase on the Development of Anorexia Nervosa Andrew Callan In humans, an eating disorder can manifest in many different ways. One of the most common eating disorders is Anorexia nervosa, which is described as an immense fear of gaining weight, self-starvation, and an extreme focus on one’s own body image. Anorexia Nervosa can manifest as behaviors avoidance of food, a restrictive diet of only foods deemed “clean”, an obsession with regular exercise, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crohn&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>An analysis by Andrew Callan CrohnD &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;https://vincentarelbundock.github.io/Rdatasets/csv/robustbase/CrohnD.csv&amp;quot;) head(CrohnD) ## X ID nrAdvE BMI height country sex age weight treat ## 1 1 19908 4 25.22 163 c1 F 47 67 placebo ## 2 2 19909 4 23.80 164 c1 F 53 64 d1 ## 3 3 19910 1 23.05 164 c1 F 68 62 placebo ## 4 4 20908 1 25.71 165 c1 F 48 70 d2 ## 5 5 20909 2 25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cigarette Usage Project</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This dataset lists data for cigarette sales and price for every state in the United States for each year between 1963 and 1992. This dataset also includes the per capita disposable income at the time the observation was taken, the population size, and the population size above the age of 16. I split the dataset in half where one dataset had the “year”, “sales”, and “price” variables and the other dataset had the “state”, “pop”, “pop16”, and “ndi” variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  Research Into Genetic Factors that Predispose Humans to Anorexia Nervosa
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>